<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Pre-Compilation Interception</title>
        <author>Peter Donald</author>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Introduction">
            <p>
                MetaClass provides mechanisms via which the developer can intercept
                and preprocess JavaDoc tags for a class prior to them being written
                out into the MetaClass descriptor. This allows the developer to write
                an interceptor that filters out unwanted JavaDoc tags, translates
                deprecated attributes to a non-deprecated form and performs validation
                on the remaining attributes.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="My First Interceptor">
            <p>
                All interceptors implement the
                <tt>org.realityforge.metaclass.tools.qdox.QDoxAttributeInterceptor</tt>
                interface and should extend the
                <tt>org.realityforge.metaclass.tools.qdox.DefaultQDoxAttributeInterceptor</tt>
                base class. By extending DefaultQDoxAttributeInterceptor the developer
                is less likely to have broken code if the QDoxAttributeInterceptor interface
                changes in the future.
            </p>
            <p>
                For example a developer could decide that they wanted to filter out all
                of the standard JavaDoc attributes such as '@version', '@author' etc as
                they are not used in their application and only increase the size of the
                generated metadata descriptor. To do this the developer could just filter
                out any attribute that has a name equal to a predefined set of names.
                The following source code performs that attribute filtering.
            </p>
            <source><![CDATA[
public class StandardJavadocStripper
    extends DefaultQDoxAttributeInterceptor
{
    public Attribute processClassAttribute( JavaClass clazz,
                                            Attribute attribute )
    {
        return processAttribute( attribute );
    }

    public Attribute processFieldAttribute( JavaField field,
                                            Attribute attribute )
    {
        return processAttribute( attribute );
    }

    public Attribute processMethodAttribute( JavaMethod method,
                                             Attribute attribute )
    {
        return processAttribute( attribute );
    }

    private Attribute processAttribute( final Attribute attribute )
    {
        final String name = attribute.getName();
        if( name.equals( "version" ) ||
            name.equals( "author" ) ||
            name.equals( "return" ) ||
            name.equals( "exception" ) ||
            name.equals( "throws" ) ||
            name.equals( "param" ) )
        {
            return null;
        }
        else
        {
            return attribute;
        }
    }
}
]]></source>
        </section>
        <section name="Using the Interceptor">
            <p>
                After the developer has written the interceptor they have to
                get the ant task to use the interceptor. This is done by adding
                a child element &lt;interceptor/&gt; into the task. This element
                has one attribute indicating the name of the interceptor class
                to use and contains a child &lt;classpath/&gt; element that defines
                where the .class files for interceptor are loaded from. See below
                for an example of how to use the above interceptor. Any number of
                Interceptors can be added and each interceptor will be invoked
                in turn until one filters out the attribute or until there are no
                more interceptors left.
            </p>
            <source><![CDATA[
<metaclassGen destDir="target/classes">
    <fileset dir="src/java"/>
    <interceptor name="example.intercept.StandardJavadocStripper">
        <classpath>
            <pathelement location="myInterceptor.jar"/>
        </classpath>
    </interceptor>
</metaclassGen>
]]></source>
        </section>
    </body>

</document>
