<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Attribute Model</title>
        <author email="peter at realityforge.org">Peter Donald</author>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Introduction">
            <p>
                MetaClass stores metadata about program elements such as classes,
                methods and fields. The metadata is packaged in discrete units named
                Attributes. Multiple attributes can be attached to each programming
                element. All attributes have a name and attributes can optionally
                contain either textual content or parameters. Parameters are key-value
                pairs that are associated with the attribute.
            </p>
            <p>
                Attributes with just a name are useful to mark a component as supporting
                a feature or capability. For example a developer could markup a class with
                the attribute named "dna.component" to indicate that the class conformed to
                the rules of being a component in the DNA framework.
            </p>
            <p>
                Attributes with parameters are the most common form of attribute.
                An example usage of a parameterized attribute would be to mark up a
                method with the attribute named "mx.method" to indicate that the method
                is to be exposed to the management subsystem (usually JMX). The "mx.method"
                attribute may have parameter named "displayString" that indicates the
                string exposed to user when it is presented in the UI and the parameter
                "impact" that indicates whether the method is just informational or will
                change system operation. Below is an example of this attribute represented
                as javadoc tags and xml elements.
            </p>
            <source><![CDATA[
@mx.method displayString="My Magic Method for Returning Info" impact="INFO"

<attribute name="mx.method">
  <param name="displayString" value="My Magic Method for Returning Info"/>
  <param name="impact" value="INFO"/>
</attribute>
]]></source>
            <p>
                Attributes with text content are a catch-all attribute that allows the
                developer to associate arbitrary string data with a programming element.
            </p>
            <source><![CDATA[
@version $Revision: 1.1 $ $Date: 2003-08-31 06:13:01 $

<attribute name="version" value="$Revision: 1.1 $ $Date: 2003-08-31 06:13:01 $"/>
]]></source>
         </section>
    </body>

</document>
